## **Doston Nabotov**

📞 +37128115853 🛮 dostonnabotov@gmail.com 👂 Riga, Latvia

As a frontend developer, I have a passion for building intuitive and user-friendly experiences. When I'm not coding, you can find me curled up with a good book or scouring GitHub for "help wanted" issues to contribute to. I am also an avid tech blogger, sharing my thoughts and experiences with the community.

## Education

### **Computer Science,** *Riga Technical University*

10/2021 - present

• Relevant coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms, Database Management, Operating Systems, Discrete Mathematics

Riga, Latvia

# Professional Experience

### **Head Teaching Assistant,** *Progress LTC*

06/2021 - 12/2021

- Mentored over 300 students to master their English skills and assisted them to apply for IELTS, CEFR and TOEFL exams
- Bukhara, Uzbekistan
- Developed innovative teaching techniques, which resulted in over 40% rise in students' engagement
- Managed calls and correspondence with parents and clients, providing updates and addressing any concerns

### Sales Assistant, Startup Company

10/2020 - 04/2021

- Contributed to the sales team in customer service, handling customer inquiries and resolving customer complaints
- Bukhara, Uzbekistan
- Maintained up-to-date customer records, reducing customer data errors by 15%

### **Production Team Lead,** *Maruf's Furniture*

05/2018 - 08/2020

- Assisted the team in overseeing the day-to-day operations of the production line
- Promoted to Production Team Lead (02/2020)
- Provided guidance and support to over 6 team members, and conducted quality
- Bukhara, Uzbekistan
- checks on finished products, resulting in a 10% decrease in defects

# Projects

### **Direct Measurements Calculator,** *Developer*

10/2022 – present

- Designed and implemented a maintainable, interactive calculator using Agile
- Eliminated 80% of manual computation, involving complex Physics equations

### Cinema Universe, System Analyst

09/2022 - 12/2022

- Coordinated tasks and timelines for a team of 15 members and successfully conducted over 20 client interviews
- Collaborated with the design team on high-fidelity Figma prototype
- The project received the 2nd place out of 10 entries in the contest.

# 🛊 Skills

### **Proficient**

Intermediate

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Sass

React, NextJS, TypeScript, Tailwind

#### **Familiar**

**Tools and Design** 

PostgreSQL, Java, Python, Eleventy

Git, GitHub, Netlify, Figma